ILGWU Legal Department Donnelly Garment Company v. ILGWU Records 5780/162
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Legal Department Donnelly Garment Company v. ILGWU Records
1935-1943
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/162
6 cubic feet
6 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Contains transcripts, briefs, and other legal documents relating to Donnelly Garment Company v. ILGWU.
5521553
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, June 10, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
From very early on in its existence, the ILGWU had need for legal counsel, and this was handled in the union's main offices in cooperation with hired attorneys. As the union grew and especially after the passage of the Taft-Hartley Act in 1947, the union found cause to establish a Legal Department. The department provided general legal counsel to the union and its affiliates, worked to develop collective bargaining agreement terms, and represented the ILGWU in litigation and arbitration. After the formation of the Master Agreements Department in 1965, the responsibilities for developing CBA terms shifted to the new department.
Scope and Contents
The Legal Department records do not comprehensively document the ILGWU legal activities, instead focusing on specific cases or series of cases.
Two ILGWU cases are documented in the Legal Department records. The first case involved the Kellwood Corporation, and the second involved the Donnelly Garment Company. The records relating to the Kellwood case (5780/107, 5780/107 AV, 5780/107 P) include court documents, correspondence and memoranda, surveys of strikers, organizing leaflets and newsletters (from both the union and the company), Steve Honeyman's draft accounts of the strike, audio and transcripts of Honeyman's interviews with ILGWU members and staff, newspaper clippings, photographs, and other printed material. The Donnelly Garment Company's case against the ILGWU is documented primarily through transcripts of the case, legal briefs, and related court documents.
Records on series of cases are the most general and extensive of the Legal Department records. They include records on ILGWU cases in the U.S. courts (5780/081), records documenting cases before the National War Labor Board (5780/085), and records relating to a wide variety contract negotiations, arbitration proceedings, and courts cases (5780/063).
Researchers may find complementary material in the other parts of the ILGWU records, such as the papers of the international leadership, especially the papers of ILGWU presidents (Series IV); the records of local unions in instances where these affiliates were involved in litigation or arbitration (Series III); and the collective bargaining agreements (Series VI). Related collections at the Kheel Center include decisions of the Coat and Suit Industry's Impartial Chairman (6036/015) and decisions of the Dress Industry's Impartial Chairman (6036/017).
This collection soley focuses on legal documents relating to the Donnelly Garment Company, including transcripts, briefs, and cases.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/107: ILGWU Legal Department Records 5780/107 AV: ILGWU Legal Department Audio-Visual Materials 5780/107 P: ILGWU Legal Department Photographs 5780/081: ILGWU Legal Department Records 5780/063: ILGWU Legal Department Records
Women's clothing industry--United States.; Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States.; Clothing workers--United States.; Industrial relations--United States.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
5521553
- Transcript, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Transcript. Vol.1, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Pgs. 1-967.
- Transcript. Vol.2, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Pgs. 968-1835.
- Transcript. Vol.1, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Pgs. 1-967. Second copy
- Transcript. Vol.2, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Pgs. 968-1835. Second copy
- Transcript. Vol.3, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Pgs. 1836-2218
- Transcript. Vol.4, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Pgs. 2219-3030
- Transcript. Vol.5, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Pgs. 3031-4190
- Transcript., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Pgs. 1836-2791
- Transcript., 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Pgs. 2792-3566
- Transcript. Vol.6, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Pgs. 4191-5103.
- Transcript. Vol.7, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Pgs. 5104-5752.
- Transcript. Vol.8, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Pgs. 5753-6580
- Transcript. Vol.6, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Pgs. 4191-5103. Second copy
- Transcript. Vol.7, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Pgs. 5104-5752. Second copy
- Index., 1939 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Plaintiff's Case. Transcript. Vol.1, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Pgs. 1-138(10)
- Plaintiff's Case. Transcript. Vol.2, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Pgs. 138(11)-388
- Plaintiff's Case. Transcript. Vol.3, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Pgs. 389-552
- Plaintiff's Case. Transcript. Vol.4, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Pgs. 553-638
- Plaintiff's Case. Transcript. Vol.5, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  Pgs. 639-777
- Plaintiff's Case. Transcript. Vol.6, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Pgs. 778-852
- Plaintiff's Case. Transcript. Vol.7, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Pgs. 853-1034
- Intervener's Case. Transcript, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Pgs. 1035-1282
- Defendant's Case Transcript. Vol.1, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Pgs. 1283-1365
- Defendant's Case Transcript. Vol.2, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  Pgs. 1366-1411(91-e)
- Defendant's Case Transcript. Vol.3, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Pgs. 1413-1670
- Defendant's Case Transcript. Vol.4, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Pgs. 1671-1927(1)
- Defendant's Case Transcript. Vol.5, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  Missing
- Defendant's Case Transcript. Vol.6, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Pgs. 2156(1)-2397
- Defendant's Case Transcript. Vol.7, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Pgs. 2398-2556(1)
- Statement of Evidence. Vol.1, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Pgs. 1-340
- Statement of Evidence. Vol.2, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Pgs. 341-659
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol.1, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  Pgs. 1-200
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol.2, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Pgs. 201-318
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol.3, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Pgs. 319-443
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol.4, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Pgs. 444-663
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol.5, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  Pgs. 664-813
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol.6, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Pgs. 814-957
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol.7, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Pgs. 958-1053
- National Labor Relations Board Case. Vol. 8, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Pages 1054-1115
- David Dubinsky, et al. [Folder 1 of 4], 1943 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Pgs. 1-228
- David Dubinsky, et al. [Folder 2 of 4], 1943 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Pgs. 229-495
- David Dubinsky, et al. [Folder 3 of 4], 1943 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Pgs. 496-693
- David Dubinsky, et al. [Folder 4 of 4], 1943 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Pgs. 694-782
- Injuction Case. Vol. 1, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Injuction Case. Vol. 2, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Injuction Case. Vol. 3, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Injuction Case. Vol. 4, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Injuction Case. Vol. 5, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Briefs, 1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Labor Board Case, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 11)